NASER AHMADI

(+98) 9189227001

Naserahmadi3002@gmail.com

Q Tehran, Iran

BIOSTATISTICIAN & DATA SCIENTIST

ABOUT ME

I am a logical, hardworking and committed Biostatistician with a passion for data and information. I possess strong communication skills, and I have more than 5 years' experience in Biostatistician, data analysis, interpretation and presentation. I am extremely organized with a keen eye for detail, and I always ensure that the work is completed on time and to a high standard. I am currently looking for a challenging new statistical role in which to develop my analytical skills.

EDUCATION

Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran

MSc Biostatistics
2015 - 2018

Razi university, kermanshah

BSc Statistics

2009 - 2015

EXPERTISE

Programing:

- R programing
- STATA
- SQL
- SPSS
- PASS

Research:

- · Statistical modeling
- · data wrangling
- Survey design
- survey analysis
- sample size calculation

EXPERIENCE

freelance data analyst

2016 - Present

Biostatistician

July 2017 - June 2022

Non-Communicable Diseases Research Center

During the time I worked in NCDRC, I've gained the following achievements: I have participated in the process of conducting national survey studies which improve the health status of the country. Also, facing such data allowed me to learn high-level skills for problem-solving. Moreover, I have contributed to all stages of STEPS 2021 from the study design to generating final reports, including sampling framework design, sample size calculation, determining the weights, Visualization, etc. As well, I had involved in analyzing other 7 previous STEPS studies which have been conducted in Iran from 2005 to 2016. Some of the articles presented in my resume are extracted from these researches. Working in such a professional environment has made me an expert in statistical programming, especially in R language and STATA software, SQL data management, and PowerBI. Eventually, complex statistical modeling knowledge was the other attainment that I got in this period. During this period, in addition to the experiences mentioned above, I improved my skills in statistical programming, especially STATA and R software. Also, I improved my skill in working with data management software such as SQL. I got involved with complex statistical models for data analysis, which led to increased my abilities in the field of statistical analysis.

Biostatistician

June 2022 - Present

CinnaGen Biotechnology company

Since I have been working in the CinnaGen. My main task is reviewing clinical trial studies and preparing dashboards for regulatory and business development groups using PowerBI. And I have been able to gain good experiences from clinical trial studies and working with PowerBI software.



RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

NCD Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC) Member

WHO Collaborating Centre on NCD Surveillance and Epidemiology, London, England | 2022-Present

LANGUAGES

- Persian
- English
- Arabic

PROJECTS

- STEPwise approach to NCD risk factor surveillance (STEPS) 2021 (NIMAD)
- STEPwise approach to NCD risk factor surveillance (STEPS) 2016 (NIMAD)
- Iran Quality of Care in Medicine Program (IQCAMP) (NIMAD)
- IraPEN Program Cost Analysis(WHO), Funded by World Health Organization (WHO)
- COVID-19 Epidemiological Study A report to the World Health Organization , Funded by
 World Health Organization (WHO)

PUBLICATIONS

Rising rural body-mass index is the main driver of the global obesity epidemic in adults| Nature

Worldwide trends in hypertension prevalence and progress in treatment and control from 1990 to 2019: a pooled analysis of 1201 population-representative studies with 104 ... | The Lancet

Height and body-mass index trajectories of school-aged children and adolescents from 1985 to 2019 in 200 countries and territories: a pooled analysis of 2181 population-based ... | The Lancet

Repositioning of the global epicenter $\,$ of non-optimal cholesterol | $\,$ Nature

Heterogeneous contributions of change in population distribution of body mass index to change in obesity and underweight| Elife

Insight into blood pressure targets for universal coverage of hypertension services in Iran: the 2017 ACC/AHA versus JNC 8 hypertension guidelines | BMC Public Health

Global, regional, and national quality of care of ischaemic heart disease from 1990 to 2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017 | European journal of preventive cardiology

How the scientific community responded to the COVID-19 pandemic: A subject-level time-trend bibliometric analysis | PloS one

The trend of interpersonal violence mortality at national and provincial levels in Iran from 1990 to 2015| Journal of interpersonal violence

Evaluation of the effect of fixed speed cameras on speeding behavior among Iranian taxi drivers through telematics monitoring | Traffic injury prevention

A New Application of Louvain Algorithm for Identifying Disease Fields Using Big Data Techniques | Journal of Biostatistics and Epidemiology

Lifestyle modification strategies for controlling hypertension: How are these strategies recommended by physicians in Iran? | Medical Journal of the Islamic Republic of Iran

The global, regional, and national burden and quality of care index (QCI) of colorectal cancer; a global burden of disease systematic analysis 1990–2019| PloS one

Trend and pattern of using herbal medicines among people who are aware of their diabetes mellitus: results from National STEPs Surveys in 2005 to 2011 in Iran| Journal of Diabetes & Metabolic Disorders

Low-quality domestic automobiles continue to threaten lives in Iran: economic instability as the potential contributor | Archives of Iranian Medicine

The mortality rate from self-harm in Iran I Public health

Global and regional burden and quality of care of non-rheumatic valvular heart diseases: a systematic analysis of Global Burden of Disease 1990–2017 | International Journal for Quality in Health Care

Safety and immunogenicity of an inactivated virus particle vaccine for SARS-CoV-2, BIV1-CovIran: findings from double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase I and II ... | BMJ open

Red flags of poor prognosis in pediatric cases of COVID-19: the first 6610 hospitalized children in Iran | BMC pediatrics

National and Subnational Trends of Incidence and Mortality of Female Genital Cancers in Iran; 1990–2016| Archives of Iranian Medicine

The effect of non-punitive peer comparison and performance feedback on drivers' behavior using the telematics: the first randomized trial in Iran | Journal of safety research

Age, period and cohort analysis of smoking prevalence in Iranian population over a 25-year period | Archives of Iranian Medicine

Quality of care of peptic ulcer disease worldwide: A systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 1990–2019 | PloS one

Expansion of the quality of care index on breast cancer and its risk factors using the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019 | Cancer Medicine

Current Inequities in Smoking Prevalence on District Level in Iran: A Systematic Analysis on the STEPS Survey | Journal of Research in Health Sciences

National and provincial population-based incidence and mortality of skin cancer in Iran; 1990–2016 | Asia-Pacific Journal of Clinical Oncology

Bone Marrow Transplant Survival Data Analysis Using Simple Models And Mixture Weibull | Zanko Journal of Medical Sciences

Use of Bayesian Mixture Models in Analyzing Heterogeneous Survival Data: A Simulation Study | Journal of Biostatistics and Epidemiology

REFERENCES

Prof. Farshad Farzadfar

Scientist at Surveillance, Monitoring and Reporting Noncommunicable Diseases Department, World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.

farzadfarf@who.int

Prof. Negar Rezaee

Assistant professor at Non-Communicable Diseases Research Center (NCDRC), Tehran University Of Medical Sciences

n.rezaei81@yahoo.com

Prof. Shirin Djalalinia

Associate Professor of Epidemiology, Vice Chancellery for Research & Technology, Iran Ministry of Health and Medical Education.

shdjalalinia@gmail.com

